Guide to the William R. Perl papers, 1925-1998 MS2026
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Legal files, 1974-1979; MS2026 Series 5; 0.25 Linear feet
  The series documents United States vs. William R. Perl (76-0369-N). Included in this series are photocopies from the Federal Bureau of Investigation's file on Perl, as well as photocopies of legal briefs, motions, testimony transcripts and newsclippings. Some original correspondence is included. All materials are from 1974-79, though some items are not dated.
  - Correspondence relating to WRP's FBI file, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - FBI file, [folder 1 of 3], undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - FBI file, [folder 2 of 3], undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - FBI file, [folder 3 of 3], undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence relating to WRP's FBI file, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Transcripts of phone conversations between WRP and Reuben Lev Tov, 1976 May-June (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Indictment before Grand Jury, 1976 June (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Testimony of William McIntosh, 1976 June 28 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1976 July (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Motions filed, 1976 July (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and notes regarding WRP's defense fund, 1976 July - 1977 January (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Motions filed, and responses, 1976 August (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence and notes, 1976 August (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Reply memorandum, 1976 August (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1976 September-December (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Report of investigation on Reuben Lev-Tov, 1976 October (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Newsclippings, 1976 November - 1977 February (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Motion for a new trial, 1976 December (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Notes, 1976 December - 1977 January (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1977 January (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1977 February-December (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of sentencing, 1977 February (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Probation report, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1978 March-May (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Petitions and decisions relating to appeal, 1978 September-October (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Proceedings and statements, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Biographical sketch of Nathan Lewin, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous writings, undated; MS2026 Series 6; 0.25 Linear feet
  The series contains contains 6 folders of poems, short stories, essays and other writings by William R. Perl. These writings do not seem to relate to Perl's activism or professional career. Most are undated and/or incomplete. Of interest is a substantial unpublished essay about the history of pipe smoking. Dated writings in this series are arranged in chronological order, followed by undated writings (in alphabetical order by title) and incomplete writings.
  - "In San Sebastian und Burgos. Bilder aus dem Spanischen Burgerkrieg." Neue Freie Press no.25831, 1936 August 09 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Wiener Wasche, 1937 May-September (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "The Tower of Babel,", 1950 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "From Adam to the Astronauts, the Art and Joys of Pipe Smoking,", undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - "The Man of the Ice Age Invents Writing,", undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Poems, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "Reise is Afrikanische Hinterland,", undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Incomplete writings, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1939-1997; MS2026 Series 7; 0.25 Linear feet
  The series consists of 2 folders of business cards and letters sent to Perl on various subjects, apparently unrelated to his activism or career. Letters date from 1939 to 1997. They are arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent, with unattributed letters filed at the end of the series.
  - Correspondents A-K and business cards, 1939-1997 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Correspondents M-Z and unattributed, 1949-1997 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Mixed media, 1920-1990; MS2026 Series 8; 1.5 Linear feet
  The series consists of photographs, audio recordings, and oversize documents.
  Photographs (14 folders) have been grouped together by topic, with folders filed in rough chronological order. Folders relating to the Malmedy War Crimes Trial and Jewish Activism contain numerous small (approximately 2" x 3") photographs, while other folders contain a single photograph. Nearly all photographs are undated, and persons in them are mostly unidentified.
  The bulk of Audio Recordings (10 audiocassettes and 1 vinyl record) appear to relate to the transport of European Jews to Palestine by William R. Perl and his associates in the 1930s and 1940s. The recordings appear to have been made during the mid-1970s, and some discussion is entirely in German. William R. Perl frequently acts as interviewer or translator, but other participants in the discussions are not always identified. Audio Recordings are not arranged in any order.
  Oversized items (12 items) consist primarily of poster advertizements for Perl's public speeches and for Jewish activism groups. They are arranged chronologically, and date from 1928 to 1987, with some items not dated.
  - Photographs: WRP and Zionist fraternity members, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: WRP and Lore Perl, Circa 1960 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: WRP and Lore Perl, Circa 1975 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Photographs: Lore Perl, Circa 1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Photographs: German soldiers involved in Malmedy massacre, Circa 1946 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: WRP at Malmedy war crimes trial, Dachau, Circa 1946 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: Images for Four Front War and Operation Action [some not used], undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: Jewish Defense League protests, Circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: WRP at outdoor prayer meeting, Circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: WRP, Meir Kahane and others at meetings, rallies and protests, Circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: WRP giving speech, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Photographs: WRP at demonstration, Circa 1975 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Photographs: Miscellaneous group photographs including WRP, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Photographs: Miscellaneous images, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Audio Recordings: Speech by King Hussein, [vinyl record, 45rpm], undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Audio Recordings:Cassette, 1975 June 28 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    General note
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: "Kladovo: Translation of Mr. [illegible] article: 2 Czars + 1 Queen."Label, Side B: [blank] Speakers: Simon Letina and WRP Approximate running time: 45 minutes Date: June 28, 1975 Description: English translation of story by Naftali Gadalia
  - Audio Recordings:Cassette, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: "Bill Perl on Fred Fisk Show" Label, Side B: [blank] Speakers: Fred Fisk Shear and WRP Approximate running time: 90 minutes Description: discussion in English about Perl's book The Four-Front War and Perl's efforts in transporting European Jews to Palestine
  - Audio Recordings:Cassette, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: "[illegible] trip of 54 Pg. 88-91, 63 & 64" Label, Side B: "[illegible], pp 88-99 54, 95, 381 [illegible]" Speakers: WRP and Ami [?] Approximate running time: 90 minutes Description: translation to English from Hebrew of Elpi [?] by Lazar [?] and other books
  - Audio Recordings:Cassette, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: "Pg. 82 British [illegible] 106-108 [illegible] Label, Side B: [illegible] Speakers: WRP, Ami [?], and one untified speaker Approximate running time: 90 minutes Description: translation to English from Hebrew, regarding British measures against the transport of Jews to Palestine
  - Audio Recordings:Cassette, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: [illegible] Label, Side B: "empty" Speakers: WRP and untified speaker Approximate running time: 45 minutes Description: translation to English from German, regarding Jews' journeys about ships on the Danube.
  - Audio Recordings:Cassette, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: [illegible] Label, Side B: "empty" Speakers: WRP and two untified speakers Approximate running time: 20 minutes Description: discussion regarding journey to Palestine
  - Audio Recordings:Cassette, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: [illegible] Label, Side B: [illegible] Speakers: WRP and several untified speakers Approximate running time: 75 minutes Description: discussion in German of journey in ships to Palestine
  - Audio Recordings:Cassette, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: "Rico Schick's report" Label, Side B: "empty" Speakers: WRP Approximate running time: 90 minutes Description: discussion in German and English regarding journeys on ships
  - Audio Recordings:Cassette, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: "[illegible] Mrs. Schneider" Label, Side B: "Mr. Gutmacher" Speakers: WRP, Judith Bentwich, Ms. Schneider and one untifed speaker Approximate running time: 90 minutes Description: discussion in German regarding journeys on ships
  - Audio Recordings: Cassette, 1975 June 23 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: "Mrs. Malka Haberman translates David Hachen's "Time to Tell"" Label, Side B: "Mrs. Malka Haberman translates David Hachen's "Time to Tell"" Speakers: WRP and Malka Haberman Approximate running time: 90 minutes Date: June 23, 1975 Description: translation of Hachen's "Time to Tell"
  - Audio Recordings:Cassette, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    [From original finding aid]: Label, Side A: [illegible] Label, Side B: [illegible] Speakers: WRP and untified speakers Approximate running time: 90 minutes Description: discussion in German and English regarding journeys on ships
  - Oversized Materials: Diploma, Hochschule fur Welthandel in Wien, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Materials: Diploma, Universitatis Letterarum Vindobonensis, 1930-1940 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Materials: Poster, "The Trail You Leave in Ink,", undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Materials: Poster, "Approaches to Juvenile Delinquency: Youth in a Changing Era,", 1963 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Materials: Poster, "Juvenile Violence in the World Today,", 1964 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Materials: Certificate of retirement, U.S. Armed Forces, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Materials: Poster, Violence in the United States,", 1968 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Materials: Poster, Union of Councils for Soviet Jews, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Materials: Poster, Americans for a Secure Israel, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Oversized Materials: Flyer, reception for WRP by U.S. Senate, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Oversized Materials: Image, Vladimir Jabotinsky, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Oversized Materials: Poster, Jewish Defense League, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)